[Hajime Shacho ending]
Fancy.
Best regards.
Q-Side Creators File Our guest this time is GuruConnect.
This is GuruConnect. Nice to meet you.
Thank you for watching.
I see that. You two have been working together for a long time, haven't you?
That's right. Actually, we have known each other for a long time.
I came to Tokyo from Kansai,
I think we have known each other for about the first 15 years or so after I came to Tokyo.
How did you get to know each other?
How did we get to know each other?
But we first met when I saw GURU perform live.
GURU CONNECT is a band of five brothers,
I first saw GURU CONNECT perform live,
At that time, I was only the bassist.
You didn't do any trackmaking or anything like that, right?
It was like a black history.
I had a great impression of the band at that time. They showed up at a live house wearing a work clothes-like jumper that made them look like they were on their knees,
I was very impressed by the way he showed up at the live house wearing a jumper that looked like a work shirt, like he was on his knees,
I knew SATOSHI first,
I knew SATOSHI first, and I was looking forward to seeing SATOSHI's brother today,
I was looking forward to seeing SATOSHI's brother, and I thought he was a little bit cool,
SATOSHI-san was holding the bass guitar and holding the bass guitar,
The bass was groovy and really cool,
And didn't he play with his back turned a little bit?
But he really looked like he was coming home from a part-time job.
He was wearing the same clothes and playing just like that, and he looked so cool.
I was really impressed. That was our first encounter.
GURU is a cool bassist, and he is still making tracks,
I have been checking out his music for a long time,
I have been checking out his music for a long time, and I have also seen him perform live a little bit,
I also have my own event called CALPUR,
I've also offered to have them perform at an event I'm running called "Calpool",
I had always wondered if there would be an opportunity to work with him in singing.
GURU-san, you have been actively releasing solo works,
You have been actively releasing solo works, but you have also been featuring various singers and rappers,
You yourself call on various singers, rappers, etc., and produce each song,
When I heard the song you did with NAOKO, I thought, "Wow!
When I heard the song you did with NAOKO, I thought, "Wow, this is it! I thought, "Wow, this is it!
Affordance?
Yes, that's right. It was the ideal I had always wanted to try,
I thought, "Wow, this is great,
I thought, "Wow, that's great, maybe now is a good time to ask for help.
I thought that now would be a good time to ask you to do it.
That was about a year ago.
I went back and looked at it today, and it was exactly one year ago.
How was it when you came?
He said, "Let's do it.
Yes, that's right. I'm just going to tell you what happened then,
I said, "Call me, this is the kind of group, but I can't ask you to do it,
I said, "I've done this kind of thing in the past, and I wanted to make something like this,
I'm not an idol.
I thought they would turn me down,
I thought they would turn me down, but they said, "I think we can do this, so we'll do it.
The key point is that I thought I could do it.
Because it was Batten Girls University and because it was you, Mr. Sugimoto.
I've heard that,
I felt that I was allowed to do it without any restrictions.
There are things you can do and things you can't do.
I felt like I could do it, or rather, I felt like I could do it,
I felt like I could do it, or rather, I felt like I could do it well.
That's what I was looking for,
I knew that what Mr. Guru was looking for was what he could imagine,
After that, I thought I would have a meeting with him pretty soon,
I asked him to come to my office for a meeting,
When I asked him to come to my office, he said that he had already made it on his way there,
It was like, I've already made it on the way here,
I don't know what they made this time,
They let me listen to the first demo, which was really like a motif,
It's exotic.
It's dancehall,
I was like, "What? I was like, "What?
I asked him to go for dance music, electro, and beat beat beat,
Dancehall?
What? I was like, "What?
Is the first demo from that time pretty close to the current song?
The orchestra was already like that.
It was like that.
But I think I made it after we decided to go with Daoko.But I think I made it after we decided to go with Daoco.
Yes, I think so.
In our talks on the phone and so on,
I'll do the sound production for the beat beat,
But what about the lyrics? But what about the lyrics?
But Daoko was the best choice.
She really understood what we were talking about.
And that's when I decided to ask Daoko to do it,
I decided to offer it to Daoko just then.
I decided to offer it to Daoko because we were going to do it with her, and that's how the beat came to be,
But I can't connect the two.
But I made it with the image of making it for Daoko.
I see.
I think that would probably make it more interesting.
But it is really strange that that beat was created,
I wonder how it came to be.
I guess it just happened,
There is a single song called "BEL" by Kamppanel.
It was the time when I was working on that song as well,
The beat was pretty much like a dancehall beat,
I think it may have been because the beat was very dancehall-like and that's what I wanted to do.
You have made many albums with that beat.
I was interested in some of them,
I was interested in what I heard and wondered how it would turn out if I tried it like this.
I think it was a bit like experimentation,
I was just experimenting with what I was interested in at the time,
I was just experimenting with what I was curious about at the time.
Yes, that's right.
The music you make, GURU-san, is not very much like Japanese artists,
The music you make does not sound like a Japanese artist, but it does not sound like some foreign artist,
But it also doesn't sound like some foreign artist,
I have a very strange feeling when I listen to your music. When I listen to it.
I wonder where he is from.
That's how the Nagasaki theme came to be,
The theme of Nagasaki is "Wakaran," which is a combination of Japanese culture and the Dutch culture of Europe,
The orchid is Dutch, which is European culture,
I wanted to express the mix of these three cultures in a chanpon style.
I wanted to express a mixture of these three cultures in a kind of "champon" style,
I thought I had the right person for the job.
It was like asking someone who was not from anywhere else.
When Mr. Sugimoto made the offer,
Did you have any idea of the musicality of the music?
I heard that you were working on an overall album like this.
Did you have some of the songs already released?
Yes, I have already told you about some of them.
I had already told you that it was going to have that kind of electro feel to it.
That's what I had already told you.
There are many kinds of electro, aren't there?
Yes, there are.
There is too much range.
Yes, it is.
So, well, it's usually England, right?
If it's not hardcore or something like that, you could do something like a band.
Then I'd say I really made it whatever I wanted.
Yes, that's right. It's like I made it without making any special discoveries.
It's an idol song, so it's not like I had to put in some cute sounds.
That's just the way it's supposed to be.
Oh, I see.
If you sing it.
And, well, if I wanted that, I would have asked someone else.
That's true.
Well, yes.
Yes, that's true. The world of words that Daoko creates also has a certain cuteness to it.
But I was very happy to be able to ask Daoko to write the lyrics.
I had heard from Mr. Gru that he was really great.
First of all, the music that Daoko and Gru did together was amazing,
As a lister, I thought that I could see a new side of Mr. Daoko in the songs that he and Gru did.
I asked him a lot of questions about how he made the music.
I asked him how he made the song and many other questions.
I already know what it looks like.
But I found out that he has a very interesting way of listening to the creative side of things.
I would like to see that world,
I would like to see that world, and I would like to see that through Batten's songwriting.
I wanted to open that kind of lid,
It was like I got an answer more than a comic book to a theme I didn't understand.
And it was so fast.
It was also very fast.
That's right.
I guess rappers are quick, aren't they? Lyrics, for example.
You are fast, aren't you, Daoko?
You are fast.It was quick.
The song we did together was lighthearted, and I was free at Corona, so I said, "Let's put out a song," and sent it to him,
The next day or so, we had the song ready to go. The next day, we had the song in the studio.
I had Daoko put in a tentative song, which I would like to hear again.
It was the kind of song that should be released.
It was perfect, like how cute or cool it would be if I delivered the words this way.
If you listen to it properly and do it right, it will become that, or it will become good.
If you listen to the cute voices that the members originally have, they will be buried even more.
That's why both Daoko and GURU came to sing this time, and GURU was the main director.
The atmosphere of the song is quite different from the other songs on the album. Compared to the other songs.
GURU-san is a little bit tough looking, but he is good at making kyaraben (character bento).
I am curious about that information.
He is very dexterous, isn't he?
All of his artwork is collage, which is contrary to his appearance.
You can't tell by yourself.
I can't tell by the groove, or the bass tone.
He makes character bento while making a sound like the bottom of blood, or the bottom of blood,
He also drank two glasses of sake.
Is this information necessary?
I introduced it in Dan Chu's magazine the other day.
He has a wide range of interests. I think he has a high sensitivity to culture.
I am sure that the members are also very pure and honest people.
I don't know if we were able to record the song without being overwhelmed by GURU's appearance, and if we were able to communicate with him from the heart,
I don't know if they were able to communicate with each other from the heart without being overwhelmed by GURU's appearance.
I wonder if they were able to communicate with him from the bottom of their hearts and record the song.
I was not afraid.
But there were some members who were like "I'm a fan of Naoko-san.
That suits it.
There were moments like that.
Like her face turning bright red.
That seems to make me nervous, though.
No, it does.
But I think I was happy.
I would say that it was a really unusual song, a bit unique in the album.
The vocal approach, too.
I thought it was a bit soft or not too strong, but was that a reaction of the two of you?
Yes, I think so.
But it seems to come naturally to you when you listen to the tentative song?
Please listen to it later.
It gives me energy.
So I wonder if it is very difficult to sing like that in a live performance for idols.
That's why there are not many songs like that.
That's right.
I think it was very unique to have a song with a slightly soft raspy feel to it.
But just from the song "Koono Minato," we asked a new choreographer, Kokoroen-san, to do the choreography,
I knew from the moment I received the song that I would definitely ask Kokoroen's team to choreograph the song,
The dance was interesting and a little strange,
It's not an idol-like dance at all,
It's not an idol-like dance at all, it's cool and a bit perverted, an interesting element.
I felt that the combination of these elements helped convey the worldview of the song to the audience.
It really is.
Have you seen the dance in action?
I saw it on the video.
How do you like it?
When the rehearsal was sent to me a long time ago, I thought it had a different feel to it.
It was different.
I thought it was like this.
You mean as an expression of that?
Yes, yes, yes.
I thought it would be great if it included dancing.
Yes, it is.
I think it's a pretty stoic song.
If you listen to the music alone.
It's not that it's creepy, but...,
It's not creepy, but it has an eeriness to it,
I think it has an entertainment element when you add that.
This is the first time you have provided music to an idol group.
It's the first time.
If that's the case, it's even more so. I was surprised to see how things change when dance is involved.
Have you ever collaborated with dancers?
Maybe not. I don't think so.
But you have been dancing with the vocalist without running out of skill.
I would like to think about that and make something like that.
It might be kind of nice.
If I may ask one more question,
If you could write another new song for Buck Ten, what kind of song would you like to write?
It depends on the meeting.
Like a concept.
It would be better to have a concept.
I have an idea in my head right now.
What is it?What is it?
Jungle.
Jungle?
The one that sings. A singing melody.
It's good.
I think it might be good.
Jungle.
The jungle of today.
The jungle now.
It's the same taste, isn't it?
I don't know if I should call it eccentric, but it's a little eccentric,
Dancehall is a little eccentric. Of course, the jungle is like that.
I wonder if that's the direction the group's ideas are going. It's strange, isn't it?
The theme of "dance music" and their songs are both very different from each other,
I guess you could say that the songs have no color, or they have a sense of transparency.
I wonder if the combination of dance music and songs without color, or songs with a sense of transparency, makes it easier for various imaginations to come up with ideas,
I think it would be a perfect match. The jungle is coming,
I can imagine that it would be interesting.
Sounds interesting and amazing.
I think it would probably be good. If you say so, I would love to have you make some.
But, you know, by the time Mr. Sugimoto asks for a jungle, I'm sure Guru will have a different interest.
Maybe it's already on the screen. Maybe so. I don't know, but I don't think it's a genre,
I was thinking that it would be interesting if you could make something like a chopped-up version of the members' voices or songs.
I thought it would be interesting to have them make something like that. Using voice samples and so on.
Is that possible? Wouldn't you like to hear it?
I would like to make an orchestra using only voice samples, and make something to sing with them.
Using our own voices as instruments and singing on top of them. That sounds amazing.
Please let me try that. That sounds like a lot of work.
You said you don't like to make collages. The pictures are, you know, a downer.
You said it would be a downer. Music is only uplifting no matter how much you make.
What about the song you made with the jungle and the voice, and the other two songs?
By the way, was there any music you were listening to when you were making the songs that you don't know, or did you have a reference for the kind of music you were thinking of making?
What did you listen to? How many songs were there?
Myself. There were quite a few.
Various. But something is a bit off,
What did I just listen to? I have dozens and dozens of songs.
There are dozens of songs, and I did a lot of research. I was thinking, "Let's try to incorporate some of the essence of this song.
It's probably totally different. How did you come up with this one after listening to this one?
Yes, that's right.
You made two demos for us at first, right?
That's right.
So this one I don't understand was called Demo 2.
Demo 1 was nothing yet.
After Daoko was decided, I made the beat for this "I don't know".
At first, I was making it vaguely, and I was like, "Hmmm.
The other one could go in a completely different direction.
That, too, could possibly happen.
But if you don't release the song, people won't know about it.
Even if we were communicating with one person in the process of making an album or a single,
Sometimes, there are two or three demos, and sometimes they are combined together.
Then I would look at the timing and ask for another opportunity.
Often, the songs that were not used in the demos were released as songs for other artists.
So I always feel that when I write a song or make an offer, various by-products are born.
So, not only the songs on the album, but also many other songs are being worked on at the same time, and they are in the creator's mind.
We are probably listening to them as well.
What was the first demo track like?
Yes, it was. Well, here it is. I can't play it.
Was it abstract?
I don't remember at all.
Really?
It was an upper atmosphere.
I'm curious.
I had an image that the song might go well with the themes of other prefectures, but I still don't know.
But I still don't know. Demo 2 had a much stronger impact on me.
But I am sure that when the decision to work with Daho was made, it became clear, and the song was decided upon.
So the songs are nurtured by the music.
It's as if they get a boost from the other songs.
It sounds strange, but since I chose this one, I feel like I have to polish this one.
We have heard a lot of in-depth discussions, and our guest this time was Mr. GuruConnect.
Thank you very much.